Guide to the New-York Historical Society Poster Collection [dates] PR 55
New-York Historical Society
- Series V. Political Posters, 18xx-20xx; 100 item(s) (approximately)
  - Tippecanoe (Harrison & Tyler) Log Cabin by Whigs of Buffalo, 1840 (Folder FF-1)
    Pub & Lith by Hall & Mooney. Poster features a 20x30 foot log cabin erected on March 18, 1840 by the Whigs of Buffalo and dedicated to the cause, Harrison & Tyler.
  - "Log Cabin Anecdotes. Illustrated Incidents in the life of Gen. William Henry Harrison", 1840 (Folder FF-1)
    J.F. Trow, Printer. Published by J.P. Giffing.
  - The 12th Ward Democratic Clay Club (Clay & Frelinghuysen), 1844 (Folder FF-1)
    M.Hopper Mott was president of the 12th Ward Democratic Clay Club. C.L. Carter, C.S. Miller, Marcellus Eells, and C.M. Graham, Jr. were officers.The event was held at Temerance Hall on 8th Avenue.
  - The Presidential (and Vice Presidential) Candidates. 1856 (Folder FF-1)
    Published by B.H. Day. "Brother Jonathan" Weekly Newspaper. Features 3 portraits of the Presidential candidates: Buchanan drawn by S.F. Baker, Fremont Holcombs, and Filmore drawn by Edmonds. And 3 portraits of the Vice-Presidential candidates: Breckenridge drawn by J.W. Orr, Dayton drawn by Holcombs, and Donelson, unsigned.
  - "Scene in the Park July 1860 between Genet and Kerrigan...For County Clerk Harry Genet., 1861 (Folder FF-2)
    Note on back explains that poster is a "Hand Bill against Harry W. Genet. November Election 1861"
  - "Lincoln and Johnson!", 1864 (Folder FF-2)
    Printed at the Village Record Office, West Chester, PA. Invitation to a meeting at Kennett Square held by the Committee of Vigilance (Dr. Frank Taylor & John J. Pinkerton, Esq.) to prepare for General and Presidential Elections.
  - National Republican Platform of 1868 (Grant & Colfax) (Folder FF-2)
    Published by L. John & Co. Poster features portraits of Grant and Colfax and sets out the Republican Platform as adopted at Chicago, May 21, 1868. Acquisition date(?) on front in pencil, May [19]06.
  - "You Must Make Your Choice." (Grant & Colfax), 1868 (Folder FF-2)
    2 copies. Designed by V. Miller; published by Photo-Eng. Co., N.Y. Features portraits of Washington, Lincoln, and Grant with the slogan, "National Unity." Copy 1 has acquisition date(?) on front in pencil, May 15/[19]06. Copy 2 lacks heading and is colored.
  - "National Democratic Banner of Victory, 1868." (Seymour & Blair) (Folder FF-2)
    Published by Currier & Ives. Features portraits of Horatio Seymour of New York and Frank P. Blair of Missouri and the slogan, "Peace, Union, and Constitutional Government". Acquisition date(?) on back, Nov. 20, 1928.
  - 'Leaders of the Democratic Party." (Seymour & Blair), 1868 (Folder FF-2)
    3 copies. Copy 1, acquisition date(?) on front, April 6/[19]06. Copy 2 stamped on back, New York Historical Society Folks Art Collection, Nov. 17, 1937. Poster features four caricatures drawn by Thomas Nast of "The Rioter Seymour", "The Butcher Forrest", "The Pirate Semmes", and "The Hangman Hampton".
  - Tilden and Reform (Tilden & Hendricks), 1876 (Folder FF-3)
    Rev. Chambers and Sidney T. Fairchild, Esq. to address citizens of Casenovia, New York.
  - "Cleveland & Victory! Irving Hall...17th Assembly District.", 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Lists candidates for primary elections of Inspectors and Delegates.
  - "November Scribners. Andrews' History. Regular Nominations" (Cleveland v. Blaine), 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster features portraits of Cleveland of New York and Blaine of Maine.
  - "Get Out People! And Rejoice! An Era of Good Times at Hand!" (Cleveland & Hendricks), 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Celebratory parade and torchlight procession on the election of Grover Cleveland & Thomas Hendricks.
  - 1884 Presidential and Vice-Presidential Candidates (Cleveland & Hendricks) (Folder FF-3)
    Published by James D. Gill of Springfield, MA. Poster features 4 portraits of Cleveland, Hendricks, Blaine, and Logan.
  - The Nation's Choice...James G. Blaine and John A. Logan, 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Published by H.W. Kelley, Philadelphia. This proof features portraits of Blaine and Logan and the Republican Platform. Acquisition date(?) on front, Dec. 06/[19]06.
  - "Building and Ruling the Republic...The Biographies of Blaine & Logan and Cleveland & Hendricks", 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster advertising the political book which was written by James P. Boyd and published by J.C. McCurdy & Co. Publishers, Philadelphia, Cincinnati, Chicago, and St. Louis.
  - "Who Defrauded the American People out of their Choice for President in 1876.", 1884 (Folder FF-3)
    Published by J. Edward Ireland, New York. For sale by The Advance Publishing Co. Poster features 12 portraits of J.A. Garfield, J.P. Bradley, O.P. Morton, W. Strong, G. Casenave, S.M. Kenner, G.F. Edmunds, F.T. Frelinghuysen, G.F. Hoar, S.F. Miller, J. Madison Wells, and T.C. Anderson. Acquisition date(?) on front, Sept. 21/[19]05.
  - "The Whole Story in a Nutshell! Harrison's Ideas!...Cleveland's Ideas!", 1888 (Folder FF-3)
    Published by Yale Publishing Co., N.Y. Poster features portraits of Harrison and Cleveland superimposed on maps of the United States and information on the partys's platforms. Acquisition date(?) on back, Sept. 9, 1949.
  - "Campaign '88 Specimen Sheet. Moss Engraving Co. 535 Pearl St., New York.", 1888 (Folder FF-3)
    Published by Moss Engraving Co. Features caricatures of Benjamin Harrison, Levi Morton, Grover Cleveland, and Allan Thurman.
  - "Cleveland's Sweep!! 287 Electoral Votes!!!, 1892 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster features caricatures from the Philadelphia Record and the Chicago Globe and articles from the Philadelphia Times, the New York Sun, the New York Tribune, and the Public Ledger.
  - "The Tammany Tiger must go. Let the Tail go with the Hide", 1894 (Folder FF-3)
    Small card featuring a tiger's hide on front and a poem to the end of Tammany on the back. Published by the Committee of Seventy.
- Series VI. Theater Posters, 17xx-19xx
- Series VI.1 Motion Picture Posters, 1890-20xx
  - Stills -- "Priscilla about to be put in the Stocks for Witchcraft" from 'When Broadway was a Trail', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "Trial of Henry Minnet" from 'When Broadway was a Trail', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF-3)
  - Stills -- Still from Edward Curtis's photo drama, "In the Land of the Head Hunters", 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Native Kwakwaka'wakw men (from British Columbia) in their masks and carvings. Edward Curtis was a noted photographer, and he produced this documentary exclusively starring Native North Americans for the first time. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "Overcome by the Drug" from 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features Tom Terriss in leading role on bed overcome by opium. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "Like an Avenging Spirit Jasper is Always Near" from 'The Mystery of Edwin Drood', a Shubert Feature, 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features a couple in a garden with a gentleman in the background. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Poster -- "The Kangaroo, Terrors of Old New Orleans", 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster produced by World Film Corporation of New York City and Campbell Art of Elizabeth, NJ. Poster features four scenes from the film: "Adrian Starts on his Trip of Inspection", "On Board the Barge", "The Discovery of the Tell-Tale Book", and "Buck Flint Unaided Attempts Dick Hullum's Arrest". The film was based on stories by Harris Dickson. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Poster -- "Miss Betty Nansen, the Distinguished Emotional Actress Featured by The Great Northern Film Co. in 'The Fallen Idol'", 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    The poster was produced by Acme Lith. Co. The film was a William Fox Features, Box Office Attraction Film Rental Company of New York City. The large poster features an image of Betty Nansen wearing a feathered hat, pearls and two medals. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943". Also stamped on back, "Box Office Attraction Film Rental Co. 126-30 W. 46 St. NYC....Jul 3 1914" Handwritten in pencil on back, "Betty Nansen".
  - Stills -- "A Jolly Party" from 'The Price of Treachery', 1914 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City and the WVanoak Pub. Co. of N.Y. and features a scene with a group at a table outside with one playing the accordian. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Howard Estabrook in "M'Liss" with Barbara Tennant, 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features a crowd around a man and a donkey. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a Shubert Feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Clara Kimball Young in "The Heart of the Blue Ridge", 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by World Film Corporation of New York City (Lewis J. Selznick was president and general manager). "The Heart of the Blue Ridge" was a Shubert feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Clara Kimball Young in "The Deep Purple", 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City and features an interior scene with Clara Kimball Young and Milton Sills. The film was based on a 1910 play written by Paul Armstrong and was an A. Liebler Feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features men gambling around a small table. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features "Lily" in an interior space with a couple folding an American flag. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Beatriz Michelena in "The Lily of Poverty Flat", 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features two men panning for gold. The film was based on writings by Bret Harte and was a California Motion Picture Corporation feature. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Lillian Russell in "Wildfire", a Shubert Feature, 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Lillian Russell and Lionel Barrymore in an interior space. The film was produced by the Shuberts based on a 1908 broadway play, Wildfire, by George V. Hobart and George Broadhurst. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Lillian Russell in "Wildfire", a Shubert Feature, 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    The still was produced by the World Film Corporation of New York City and features Lillian Russell in an interior space. The film was produced by the Shuberts based on a 1908 broadway play, Wildfire, by George V. Hobart and George Broadhurst. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Still from a William A. Brady Picture Plays, Inc., "What Happened to Jones" with Fred Mace, 1915 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features Fred Mace with two gentlemen near a dressing table. The film was based on a 1897 play by George Broadhurst of the same title. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Still from a William A. Brady Picture Plays, Inc., "The Ballet Girl", 1916 (Folder FF-3)
  - Stills -- Still from a William A. Brady Picture Plays, Inc., "The Ballet Girl", 1916 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by World Film Corporation of New York City. Features Alice Brady in the leading role in a bedroom scene with a man. The film was based on a novel, Carnival, by Compton MacKenzie. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- Still from "Equitable Motion Picture Corp. Presents Robert T. Haines in 'Human Cargoes'", 1916 (Folder FF-3)
    Still produced by Equitable Motion Picture Corp. (founded by Arthur Spiegel of Chicago) and features a group examining a young woman. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "Grand Central Palace Hero Land", [1917] (Folder FF-1)
    J. Carl Mueller designed the still, and Heywood Strasser & Voight Litho. Co. N.Y. published the still. Hero Land promised "The greatest spectacle the world has ever seen for the greatest need the world has ever known. British tank 'Britannia' in action". Acquisition date(?) stamped on back, Jun 18 1931.
  - Poster -- "Sincerely Douglas Fairbanks", c. 1920 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster features a smiling Douglas Fairbanks looking over a wall of some sort.
  - Poster -- Mary Pickford in "Through the Back Door", 1921 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster features an image of Mary Pickford sitting on her bed holding a doll. The movie was directed by Jack Pickford and Alfred Green with scenario by Marion Fairfax. Acquisition date(?) on back, Mar. 29, 1940.
  - Poster -- Douglas Fairbanks in "The Nut", 1921 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster features a scene with Douglas Fairbanks and Marguerite De La Motte in evening dress. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "Danse Macabre", 1922 (Folder FF-1)
    Information about the still handwritten on back: "Adolph Bolm with Ruth Page (his pupil) Olin Howland as Death in Adolph Bolm screen version of the Dance Macabre, music by C. Saint-Saens. A-2" Stamped and handwritten on back: "Dec. 5, 1933. Oct. 23, 1940". Acquisition information on back(?), "E.B. Child 1940".
  - Stills -- "Danse Macabre", 1922 (Folder FF-1)
    Information about the still handwritten on back: "Adolph Bolm with Ruth Page (his pupil) Olin Howland as Death in Adolph Bolm screen version of the Dance Macabre, music by C. Saint-Saens. B-2" Stamped and handwritten on back: "Dec. 5, 1933. Oct. 23, 1940". Acquisition information on back(?), "E.B. Child 1940".
  - Still -- from "A Woman of Paris: A Drama of Fate", 1923 (Folder FF-3)
    The still's "Country of Origin, U.S.A." Features a dining scene with Edna Purviance and Adolphe Menjou. The film was written, directed, produced and scored by Charles Chaplin. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Poster -- "D.W. Griffith's - 'Isn't Life Wonderful'", 1924 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster "made in U.S.A." Features a scene from the film directed and produced by D.W. Griffith, based on a novel by Geoffrey Moss, and starring Carol Dempster and Neil Hamilton. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Stills -- "The Enemy", 1925 (Folder FF-1)
    Still by Studio Apeda, NY, of stage play, "The Enemy". Information about the still handwritten on back: "John Wray, Fay Bainter and Jane Seymour in 'The Enemy'". Stamped and handwritten on back: "Dec. 5, 1933. Oct. 23, 1940". Acquisition information on back(?), "E.B. Child 1940".
  - Poster -- "Douglas Fairbanks in 'Don Q, Son of Zorro'", 1925 (Folder FF-3)
    Poster's "Country of Origin, U.S.A." Features a scene between Douglas Fairbanks and Mary Astor and an image of Douglas Fairbanks in full-swashbuckling regalia superimposed over an edge of the scene. Stamped and handwritten on back, "Dec. 5, 1933. Feb. 25, 1943".
  - Advertisement -- "Tarzan the Tiger", 1929 (Folder FF-2)
    Advertisement in the shape of an elephant. On the reverse side, "Tarzan the Tiger by Edgar Rice Burroughs with Frank Merrill and Natalie Kingston. New adventures, hazards, thrills. Printed in U.S.A."
  - Stills -- "William Fox Presents Lightnin' ", 1930 (Folder FF-1)
    Bottom front of still: "Made in U.S.A." Acquisition information on back (?), "T.O. Mabbott. Sept. 28, 1938".
  - Advertisement -- Carl Laemmle presents Harry Langdon and Slim Summerville in "See America Thirst", 1930 (Folder FF-2)
    The advertisement is in two pieces and features the commedians, Harry Langdon and Slim Summerville, leaning against a lamp pole with an inset image of the actress, Bessie Love. "See America First" was a Universal Picture.
  - Advertisement -- Carl Laemmle presents "East is West", 1930 (Folder FF-2)
    The advertisement which features a woman dressed in a stylized kimono is made in the U.S.A. "East is West" is a picturization of the stage play of the same name by Samuel Shipman and John B. Hymer. The Universal Picture was a Monta Bell Production, produced by Carl Laemmle, Jr. with Lupe Velez, Lewis Ayes, and Edward G. Robinson.
  - Advertisement -- Carl Laemmle presents "Dracula", 1931 (Folder FF-2)
    Advertisement was made in the U.S.A. and features an image of Dracula with an open cape holding a swooning model. "Dracula, a Universal Picture, was produced by Carl Laemmle, Jr., based on the novel by Bram Stoker, and was a Tod Browning Production.
  - Stills -- "David and Dora in their little love-nest." from David Copperfield, 1935 (Folder FF-1)
    Bottom front of still: "Country of Origin USA." "David Copperfield from the world-loved novel by Charles Dickens". Acquisition information on back (?), "T.O. Mabbott. Sept. 28, 1938".
  - Stills -- "The Rookery -- Boyhood home of Little David" from David Copperfield, 1935 (Folder FF-1)
    On bottom front of still: "Country of Origin U.S.A." and "David Copperfield from the world-loved novel by Charles Dickens". Acquisition information on back(?), "T.O. Mabbott. Sept. 28, 1938".
  - Advertisement -- "Bette Davis, Miriam Hopkins in Warner Bros. "Old Acquaintance" at the Hollywood Theater, 1943 (Folder FF-2)
    Advertisement strip copyrighted by Nathan Rubin Ads. Also includes a small advertisment for the Strand movie palace: on screen, "Princess O'Rourke"; on stage, Shep Fields & Orch. Merry Macs.
  - Advertisement -- "Cary Grant in Frank Capra's 'Arsenic and Old Lace'" at the Strand movie palace, 1944 (Folder FF-2)
    Advertisement strip by Nathan Rubin for "Broadway's Happiest Fun Show! at the Strand". On screen, "Arsenic and Old Lace" with Cary Grant (pictured), Raymond Massey, Jack Carson, Peter Lorre; on stage, Charlie Barnet, his orchestra and gala revue.
  - Poster -- Columbia Pictures presents "The Killer that Stalked New York", 1950 (Folder OSFF-4)
    The poster is copyrighted by the Columbia Pictures Corp. in 1950. The film starred Evelyn Keyes, Charles Korvin, and William Bishop. Screenplay by Harry Essex, based on Cosmopolitan Magazine article by Milton Lehman, directed by Earl McEvoy and produced by Robert Cohn. The plot of the film involves a smallpox outbreak.
  - Poster -- The Rank Organisation presents a Val Guest Production "80,000 Suspects", 1963 (Folder OSFF-4)
    The poster was printed in Great Britain. The film starred Claire Bloom, Richard Johnson, Yolande Donlan, and Cyril Cusack. Val Guest wrote the screenplay and directed the film. It was based on a novel by Elleston Trevor, and the film was shot in CinemaScope. The plot of the film involves a smallpox outbreak.
  - Advertisement -- ABC Television Network poster announcing the airing of "Roots", 1977 (Folder FF-2)
    The poster features images of the starring actors set out by the generations. It was a David L. Wolper Production based on the Alex Haley novel by the Warner Bros. Television Distribution, A Warner Communications Company. "Roots" was shown on 8 consecutive nights from January 23 to January 30, 1977.
  - Advertisement -- Broadway Dancer in Art Deco fashion, undated (Folder FF-2)
    A two part advertisement for Broadway by The Hennegan Company of Cincinnati, Ohio. It features an image of a broadway dancer with a second piece with "Broadway" written on it that could be attached to the dancer as a skirt.and then be hung up.
- Series VII. World War I Posters, 1914-1920
  The World War I Poster series, dates from circa 1914 to 1920, and consists of posters, pictorial sheets and related ephemera used by governments and organizations during the first World War to persuade citizens to enlist in various branches of the armed service, buy bonds, conserve food and fuel, provide relief, and generally support the war and aid efforts. Included in the collection is Montgomery Flagg's famous "I Want You" poster; also included are posters by Howard Chandler Christy, Alonzo Earl Foringer, Wladyslaw T. Benda, Fortunino Matania, Charles Dana Gibson, and Joseph Pennell. This series of the Poster File is divided into seven subseries: Recruitment, Monetary Appeals, Patriotic Appeals, Conservation Appeals, Relief Appeals, Organizational, and Miscellaneous.
  There is a separate inventory for this series, found at this link: World War I Posters
- Series VIIII. World War II Posters, 1941-1946; 500 item(s) (approximately)
  The collection is comprised of approximately 500 posters related to various aspects of the United States's mobilization for World War II. Topics include war financing (war bonds, donations); conservation and rationing; recruitment for the military and for the domestic workforce, including a target audience of women for the Women's Army Auxiliary Corps (WAACs), Nursing Corps, and homefront jobs; the need to avoid loose talk concerning military and defense matters; production of goods; quality and safety; general war support using patriotic, religious and other themes; and other matter.
  Most of the posters were produced by the U.S. government, though there are many produced by corporate or other private interests. Most of the posters are oriented to a national audience; a few are from New York City and have a local target audience is local. The collection also holds some posters from Canada and, to a lesser extent, the United Kingdom.
  The World War II Posters series has a separate inventory found at this link: World War II Posters
- Series IX. Other Subjects, 18xx-20xx
  [Fortunately, not a lot. item level probably worthwhile for much. Sports and other categories need to be added. Should do what we did with postcards, and go around pulling all the stray ones around here. Pull posters from ephemera.]
  Arrangement
  Chronological subseries for one-offs. Other subseries here reflect current folder headings and those can be adjusted as warranted.
  - Subseries IX.A. Chronological, 18xx-20xx
    The subseries includes a variety of subjects, too few of each to classify within one of the other topical subseries. All posters in this subseries are listed individually.
    The subseries is arranged in rough chronological order.
    - American Water Color Society. 29th Annual Exhibition., 1896 (Folder 09-01)
      Poster designed by George Wharton Edwards. Exhibition held at the National Academy of Design. On back, "The Harry A. Ogden Collection of The New York Historical Society. October 20, 1936."
    - Advertisement for a weekly, Truth, sold everywhere., circa 1896 (Folder 09-03)
      Poster features pictures of McKinley and Bryan and offers $20 in gold or silver if you are wiser than McKinley or Bryan.
    - "Never mind Chimmie, termorrow yer sells Journals..." 2 news boys (newsies), circa 1900 (Folder 09-03)